<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nasir Hossein Dad</title>
    <link>https://github.com/NasirDad/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nasir Hossein Dad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/NasirDad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Financial Frictions, Misallocation, and Average Firm-Size</title>
      <link>https://github.com/NasirDad/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://github.com/NasirDad/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Why do living standards differ so much across countries? Across time and space, we observe large differences in income per capita across countries. Factor difference between richest and poorest deciles of the income distribution are of 20 folds in 1960 to more than 50 fold in 2014. A natural question arises, what accounts for the large differences in income per capita across countries? The literature subscribes to productivity (TFP) in accounting for bulk of the differences in income per capita across countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity Losses from Financial Frictions: Self-Financing, Growth and Endogenous Productivity</title>
      <link>https://github.com/NasirDad/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://github.com/NasirDad/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this paper is two-fold. Firstly I develop a tractable general equilibrium model featuring heterogeneous agents facing financial constraints and endogenous evolution of entrepreneurial productivity. The key mechanism I explore is the interaction between growth, self-financing and misallocation. Consider an economy with underdeveloped financial system with the presence of severe financial frictions which distorts the allocation of capital across agents. This static misallocation acts as a tax on growth, because there are two competing forces that individuals are facing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The roles of Time and Cohort Effects in Rising Wealth Inequality </title>
      <link>https://github.com/NasirDad/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://github.com/NasirDad/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This paper gauges how inequality evolves over the life cycle when controlling for time and cohort effects. To differentiate between time and cohort effects we construct two alternative regression models. The first model is constructed with a full set of age and year dummies, which controls for time effects. The second model is constructed with a full set of age and cohort dummies, which controls for cohort effects. We construct age profiles and plot the corresponding coefficients for the age dummies from both regressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://github.com/NasirDad/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://github.com/NasirDad/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a third year PhD student at the University of Toronto. I studied Economics and Mathematics at Ryerson University as an undergraduate and masters in economics at Queen&amp;rsquo;s University. My parents are from Afghanistan and identify with a minority tribe referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Hazaras&amp;rdquo;. I was born in Iran (Shush) and have lived in Russia (Moscow) and currently reside in Toronto. Beside academic work, I enjoy practicing Jiu-Jitsu, film photography and traveling the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://github.com/NasirDad/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://github.com/NasirDad/contact/</guid>
      <description> Follow me on these social media platforms. Platform URL Twitter: https://twitter.com/NasirHossein22 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nasirhossein22/ GitHub: https://github.com/NasirDad </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
